

# MSc. Lukáš Buňát





🎮 Full-Stack Developer 🖥 Big Data Engineer 🖓 Business Consultant







+420 731 277 533



bunat.cz



bunatl



lukasbunat

Full-Stack Developer with the primary focus on front-end with 4+ years of experience in web/software development and data science. I have an educational background in Computer Science and Business Informatics at many different universities all over the world. I thrive on multicultural teams and enjoy resolving everyday challenges using my analytical thinking and problem-solving skills.



### **Technical Skills**

	Front-End	React.js 16.12, JavaScript ES6/2017, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass		
Full-Stack	Back-End	AWS services, serverless, Node.js, express.js, apache2, nginx		
technologies	Database	MongoDB (Mongoose, Monk), DynamoDB, MySQL, MS SQL Server, lowdb		
_	Other	Yarn, npm, webpack, parcel, react testing library, Jest, Cypress, postman		
Data Science	Python, SQL SSIS/SSAS, BI, Tableau, Hadoop, PySpark, Rapid Miner, Hive, Spark, Jupyter			
Collaboration	GIT (GitHub), JIRA, Trello, Slack, Asana, G Suite, MS Teams, Office 365			



**Freelance** 

## **Work Experience**

#### Web dev, tutor & consultant 05/2015 - Present Prague, Czech Republic

- Consult businesses, to digitalize their processes
- Building (web) automatization tools
- Build and maintain business React/WordPress websites
- Tutor university students in programming & math
- Implementing additional web apps' functionalities

05/2018-05/2019 Video services specialist O2 Czech Republic a.s. Prague, Czech Republic

- I helped to deliver the O2TV platform with 500K users
- **O2TV** is a content streaming platform built with ReactJS and supported with other JAVA SE/EE & C applications
- I integrated an audio/video player for Prague's city hall
- I maintain and develop other internal application
- The platform is available on: https://www.o2tv.cz/

#### 10/2017 - 12/2017 **Big Data Analyst** Madrid, Spain **Comillas Pontifical University**

- Analyzed Spain's power distribution system to discover consumption patterns using clustering techniques
- Analyzed data were stored in **Hadoop**, I processed them with Spark (for faster processing) and I used Hive for SQL-like interface. Code is written in PySpark
- The findings (visualized in pandas) allowed to pre-assign the necessary resources in each range of time or season

From 2014 to 2019 I had been working as a volunteer tutor at international student club at CTU.



## Featured Projects

#### **Portalo**

- Portalo is a portal that links internal and external web apps into a single portal. Users' module allows manage employees and their information stored in a database
- I created this project as part of my diploma thesis and distributed it as an open-source code
- Front-end part is written in ReactJS with Ant Design and back-end using GraphQL with DynamoDB, Lambda, IAM, Amplify and Cognito services. Hosted on AWS.

#### **EconMetrics CZ**

- The application provides company profiling, economical scoring and other multicriteria analysis using gathered and structured available public data
- Reports from EconMetrics can be used either by individuals or companies
- API enables automatization for 3rd parties
- Currently is project in development

#### **Company Business Intelligence Analysis**

- I designed and created a database in MS SQL Server based on the structure of the given raw data
- With data pumps I imported raw data from excel, txt, csv and MS Access files, using ETL operations in SQL SSIS
- Based on stored data, I built OLAP cube in SQL SSAS and graphically represented them in Tableau





New creative and innovative approaches to problem solving



Very good (cross-culture) communication for constructive teamwork



Enthusiastic and passionate about learning new things and technologies



Decisiveness and good decision-making (even uder pressure) & leadership



Effective time managment to ensure tasks' deadlines are met



## **Education**

Unive	rsity, Year(s) of Study	Field of study, Faculty	Location
STOLA EROPORTO	University of Economics and Business	Information systems and technologies  MSc. Graduate (Ing.), 06/2021	Prague,
PRAZE	2019 - 2021	Faculty of informatics and statistics	▼ Czech Republic
	Czech Technical University	Open Informatics	Prague,
	2019	Faculty of Electrical Engineering	▼ Czech Republic
(SFS)	University of Finance and Administration	Applied Informatics Undergraduate (Bc.)	Prague, Czech Republic
COLO	2018-2019	Faculty of Economics	
	Czech Technical University	Information Systems and Management	• Prague,
	2014–2018	Faculty of Information Technology	▼ Czech Republic
ETATIONAL PROPERTY OF THE PROP	Kyungpook National University	Exchange studies	Daegu,
<b>建</b>	2017	College of IT Engineering	▼ South Korea
LE LOCALITA DE LA CONTROL DE L	Indian Institute of Technology Madras	Exchange studies	Chennai,
E THE STATE OF THE	2016	Department of Computer Science	<b>▼</b> India
OHIVERS TO	Delft University of Technology	Case study of Earthquakes in Netherland	O Delft,
Moccessus.	2016	The ATHENS Programme	Netherlands
A	Mayflower College of English	Summer language school	Plymouth, United
	2012		Kingdom



# **Certificates**



CISCO Academy

CCNA 1 (2013)



Autodesk





KFN of UNESCO

Cross Culture Awereness Programme